

Summary

With 7 years of programming experience, including 4 years in Software Engineering enterprise across FinTech, E-commerce, and EdTech, I specialize in designing data-intensive applications with a focus on reliability, scalability, and maintainability. My experience spans from maintaining high-traffic services ~26K req/second and handling collaborating with 500 backend engineers to working in startups as small as 20 employees, enabling me adapt seamlessly to any environment. In my free time, I enjoy contributing to open source projects.

Contact

Pubai, United Arab Emirates

4971 54 546 1377

M kmirzavaziri@gmail.com

🔼 <u>k.mirzavaziri.com</u>

in linkedin.com/in/kmirzavaziri

Skills

Backend (Primary)

Expert in Go · Python · PHP · SQL

Experienced in Kubernetes · Docker ·
Linux · CI/CD · Django · Redis

Familiar with Nginx · Kafka · Ansible ·
MongoDB · RabbitMQ · Prometheus ·
AWS (EC2, ECS, S3, RDS) ·

Terraform

Other Stacks

Experienced in JS · HTML · CSS **Familiar with** WordPress · UI/UX (Figma) · Flutter · Dart

Education

Sharif University of Technology

M.Sc. CS, 2022 - 2023 (Drop-out)

University of Tehran

B.Sc. CS, 2017 - 2022

- Served as Chief Scientific Officer at the Scientific Association of Computer Science for 1 year.
- TA for 4 courses, including Head TA managing 3 other assistants in one course.

Work Experience



Software Engineer at Best Wing · Mar 2024 - Present (5 mos) · Dubai *An iGaming & Blockchain startup*

AWS · Terrafrom · Docker · Gitlab CI · Go · Redis · PostgreSQL · Kafka · Clickhouse

- Accelerated MVP launch by 1 month by applying Extreme Programming (XP) practices and Continuous Integration, which led to an earlier go-live.
- Automated CD on AWS by using Terraform for IaC, which increased productivity, reduced costs by 20%, and improved availability.
- Improved data processing with an event-driven architecture by integrating Kafka and ClickHouse, which handled high call volumes and enabled advanced reporting for marketing and BI teams.



Software Engineer at Divar · Jul 2022 - Mar 2024 (1 yr 9 mos) · Tehran *Alternative for Bayut in Iran with 60+ million active users.*

K8s · Docker · Gitlab CI · Go · Python · Redis · PostgreSQL · MongoDB · RabbitMQ · Kafka · Prometheus · Grafana

- Played a major role in redesigning a critical Python service in Go, leading to 99.9% uptime (up from 99.84%), sub-100 ms response times (99th percentile), a 95% reduction in average response size, increased developer productivity, and a notable decrease in call center load.
- Optimized a write-heavy service by shifting from synchronous calls to asynchronous events, resulting in higher fault tolerance, preventing data loss, and reducing resource usage by 66% (24 CPU cores and 120 GiB memory).
- Reduced CI pipeline duration to < 2min (from > 5) in a monorepo by employing caching and best practices, significantly boosting overall developer productivity across the organization.
- Maintained a critical read-heavy service with an average load of 6K+ req/s, satisfying business requirements and ensuring high availability.



Software Engineer at Avistopia · Oct 2021 - Jun 2022 (9 mos) · Tehran An EdTech startup with \$50K+ annual revenue.

 $\textit{Docker} \cdot \textit{Nginx} \cdot \textit{GitHubActions} \cdot \textit{PHP} \cdot \textit{JS} \cdot \textit{MySQL} \cdot \textit{Redis} \cdot \textit{Twig} \cdot \textit{Sass} \cdot \textit{Prometheus} \cdot \textit{Grafana}$

- Crafted a scalable LMS by leading 3 engineers under Agile, which now hosts 2500+ users and offering 70+ courses and workshops.
- Met complex business requirements for event registration by swiftly designing and developing a microservice, attracting 400+ users in the early days.



Software Engineer at Digikala · Aug 2020 - Sep 2021 (1 yr 2 mos) · Tehran

Alternative for Amazon in Iran with 41+ million active users.

 $\textit{PHP} \cdot \textit{Symfony} \cdot \textit{JS} \cdot \textit{MySQL} \cdot \textit{Redis} \cdot \textit{Twig}$

- Organized fulfillment center inbound operations by implementing a queue management system with ticket dispensers at warehouses, boosting satisfaction for sellers and suppliers.
- Enhanced warehouse security by engineering a tracking system with customizable storage constraints, resulting in \$20K monthly cost savings.



Software Engineer at Arithland · Aug 2017 - Jul 2020 (3 yrs) · Mashhad *An Educational Center promoting mathematics using creative methods.*

 $MySQL \cdot PHP \cdot JavaScript \cdot C\# \cdot HTML \cdot CSS \cdot Bootstrap \cdot WordPress$

- Reduced staffing requirements by automating competition score tracking, resulting in cost savings for the organization.
- Simplified the registration procedure by implementing a web app, leading to 21K+ students participating in events within a year.

Languages

English Farsi

Can speak fluently Native speaker